<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shankar Kumar</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shankar Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 16:35:31 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Experience</title>
      <link>/posts/work_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/work_experience/</guid>
      <description>Robert Bosch GmbH Intern at the Bosch Center for Artificial Intelligence (BCAI), Lead AI Enabler for Classical Machine Learning and Deep Learning.
Letter of Recommendation
Experience Letter
 Designed a platooning demonstrator of self-driving cars. Presented it at the Bosch AI Conference of 2019, headline of the German newspaper Handelsblatt. Implemented Deep Neural Networks for image classification, object detection, object tracking and segmentation and Logistic Regression for lane planning. Designed an Auto Regressive Integrated Moving Average (ARIMA) and Facebook’s Prophet model for time series analysis, forecasting and backcasting of solar irradiance data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>/posts/education_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 04:01:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/education_experience/</guid>
      <description>Master of Science, Computer Engineering University of Paderborn Focus areas: Pattern Recognition, Machine Learning, Embedded Systems
Master’s Thesis: Incremental Machine Learning using Support Vector Machines
 Designed an embedded machine learning system with Support Vector Machines for tackling Classification and Regression problems on Big Data with accuracies from 82% to 96% Implemented various incremental learning methods for batch and online training with approximations to reduce run time (-65%), memory (-25%) &amp;amp; computational complexity (-15%) Implemented PCA, t-SNE and Parallel Coordinate plots for visualizing high dimensional data and K-Means and Nearest Neighbor clustering methods as a test of classifiability Accelerated training and inference phases by 500% using reconfigurable hardware  [Python] [C/C++] [Verilog] [Scikit-Learn]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/posts/intro_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/intro_projects/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning Projects  Transfer Learning with the Inception V3 Network on the Stanford 40 Actions Dataset Pose Estimation with High Resolution Neural Networks - A Top-Down Approach Pose Estimation with High Resolution Neural Networks - A Bottom-Up Approach Platooning Demonstrator with Deep Learning and Computer Vision Reinforcement Learning with a Four-Legged Spider Genetic Algorithms for Hyperparameter Tuning of Neural Networks  Classical Machine Learning Projects  Similarity Measures for Music Loop Projects in the Music Maker JAM Application Imputing Solar Irradiance Data with ARIMA and Prophet Text Clustering Amazon Product Reviews with K-Means Credit Card Fraud Detection with Isolation Forest Classifier Accelerated Incremental Machine Learning using Support Vector Machines  Natural Language Processing Projects  Predict tags on StackOverflow with linear models Recognize named entities on Twitter with LSTMs Just One Context based Word Prediction using Word Embeddings Missing Word Prediction with BERT  Algorithm Projects  Conways Game of Life with MPI Mandelbrot Fractals Accelerated with Numba Travelling Salesman  Embedded System Projects  Intelligent Embedded Prosthetic Controller using Surface EMG Signal Acquistion Railway Track Tracing using Ultrasonics Automated Pill Dispencer  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/posts/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 16:35:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/resume/</guid>
      <description>Click here to download
 Certifications   Natural Language Processing
This course covered a wide range of tasks in Natural Language Processing from basic to advanced: sentiment analysis, summarization, dialogue state tracking, to name a few. It helped recognize NLP tasks in day-to-day work, propose approaches, and judge what techniques are likely to work well.
  Python for Data Science and AI
This was a kickstart to learning Python for data science, as well as programming in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Incremental Machine Learning using Support Vector Machines</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/classical_machine_learning_projects/incremental_svm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 17:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/classical_machine_learning_projects/incremental_svm/</guid>
      <description>Github link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Fraud Detection with Isolation Forest Classifier</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/classical_machine_learning_projects/credit_card_fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 17:29:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/classical_machine_learning_projects/credit_card_fraud/</guid>
      <description>Github link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict tags on StackOverflow with linear models</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/natural_language_processing/tag_prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 17:29:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/natural_language_processing/tag_prediction/</guid>
      <description>Github link
How to predict tags for posts from StackOverflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognize named entities on Twitter with LSTMs</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/natural_language_processing/twitter_lstm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 17:29:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/natural_language_processing/twitter_lstm/</guid>
      <description>Github link
How to Recognize named entities on Twitter with LSTMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similarity Measures for Music Loop Projects in the Music Maker JAM Application</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/classical_machine_learning_projects/jam_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 17:29:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/classical_machine_learning_projects/jam_test/</guid>
      <description>Github link
The 100 XML project files describe 100 songs which are consisting of parts. Each part has 8 channels and each channel can hold one music loop. Each part and loop has some features (tags) such as name, volume and active. The loops within the channels can be active or inactive. Only the active loops are considered by our network for creating a song.
  Parse the XML files and extract information</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Clustering Amazon Product Reviews with K-Means</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/classical_machine_learning_projects/text_clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 17:27:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/classical_machine_learning_projects/text_clustering/</guid>
      <description>Github link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imputing Solar Irradiance Data with ARIMA and Prophet</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/classical_machine_learning_projects/solar_irradiance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 17:27:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/classical_machine_learning_projects/solar_irradiance/</guid>
      <description>Github link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pose Estimation with High Resolution Neural Networks - A Bottom Up Approach</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/deep_learning_projects/pose_estimation_bottom_up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/deep_learning_projects/pose_estimation_bottom_up/</guid>
      <description>Github link
We are interested in the human pose estimation problem with a focus on learning reliable high-resolution representations. Most existing methods recover high-resolution representations from low-resolution representations produced by a high-to-low resolution network. Instead, our proposed network maintains high-resolution representations through the whole process. We start from a high-resolution subnetwork as the first stage, gradually add high-to-low resolution subnetworks one by one to form more stages, and connect the mutli-resolution subnetworks in parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pose Estimation with High Resolution Neural Networks - A Top-Down Approach</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/deep_learning_projects/pose_estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/deep_learning_projects/pose_estimation/</guid>
      <description>Github link
We are interested in the human pose estimation problem with a focus on learning reliable high-resolution representations. Most existing methods recover high-resolution representations from low-resolution representations produced by a high-to-low resolution network. Instead, our proposed network maintains high-resolution representations through the whole process. We start from a high-resolution subnetwork as the first stage, gradually add high-to-low resolution subnetworks one by one to form more stages, and connect the mutli-resolution subnetworks in parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography</title>
      <link>/posts/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/photography/</guid>
      <description>From the pathways of the Roman Colloseum
                  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platooning Demonstrator with Deep Learning and Computer Vision</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/deep_learning_projects/platooning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/deep_learning_projects/platooning/</guid>
      <description>Github link
Originally envisioned as a demonstrator for the Bosch AI CON 2019, the platooning system consists of two cars, a leading car and a following car. The leading car can be driven manually using a PS4 controller and the following car will autonomously follow the leading car.
In addition to this, the system currently is also capable of Object Tracking, Velocity Estimation by Optical Flow Visual Odometry and Monocular Depth Estimation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning with a Four Legged Spider</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/deep_learning_projects/reinforcement_spider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/deep_learning_projects/reinforcement_spider/</guid>
      <description>Github link
to be written soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfer Learning with the Inception V3 Network on the Stanford 40 Actions Dataset</title>
      <link>/posts/projects/deep_learning_projects/transfer_inception_stanford/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/projects/deep_learning_projects/transfer_inception_stanford/</guid>
      <description>Github link</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>